Guide to the Project Maje Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Project Maje records
1960-2005
MS 2039
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
34
(114 boxes)
The contents of the Project Maje collection reflect the professional and research interests of human rights advocate and author Edith Mirante, and draw upon more than three decades of her work in and on the border regions of Burma (Myanmar). The bulk of the materials center on issues of human rights and indigenous communities in Burma's northern and western frontiers; petroleum multinationals, deforestation, and environmental issues; and more general documents attending to the Burma's tumultuous political context.
Mirante, Edith T.
Project Maje
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Biographical / Historical
Edith Mirante was born in Newark, New Jersey and graduated from Sarah Lawrence College in 1975. Since the early 1980's, she has been actively involved in collecting and disseminating information on Burma (Myanmar), specifically regarding environmental and human rights conditions, specializing in the conditions among the Kachin, Chin, Rakhine, and Rohingya ethnic groups from Burma's northern and western frontiers. Mirante is the author of reports, popular media and encyclopedia articles, book chapters, and three monographs as of 2015 on Burma, Southeast Asia, human rights, and deforestation. She exposed the misuse of the herbicide 2,4-D in a US anti-narcotics program in Burma during the 1980's, and has testified on the country before the US Congress, European Trade Commission, and the International Labor Organization. She has also spoken at national conferences of Amnesty International USA and Rainforest Action Network, and for numerous environmental, human rights, and women's groups.
Mirante is the founder and director of Project Maje, an independent project that has been responsible for disseminating information on human rights and indigenous and environmental issues in Burma since 1986.
Scope and Contents
The contents of the Project Maje collection reflect the professional and research interests of human rights advocate and author Edith Mirante, and draw upon more than three decades of her work in and on the border regions of Burma (Myanmar). The term "Maje" refers to a bell venerated by the Apatani tribe of Arunachal Pradesh, India. This term was chosen for its symbolism and to avoid implications of ethnic favoritism in a country fraught by ethnic and religious violence. Its pronunciation is similar to that of the term for "older sister" in Burmese, which is a positive association as older sisters look after younger siblings.
The bulk of the materials center on issues of human rights and indigenous communities in Burma's northern and western frontiers; petroleum multinationals, deforestation, and environmental issues; and more general documents attending to the Burma's tumultuous political context.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into eleven series according to content and format type: I. United States and Asian press, government reports, and documents, II. Newsletters, press, documents, and women's issues, 1989-1995, III. Newsletters, press, documents, and Project Maja reports, 1996-1997, IV. Assorted documents, V. Arakan, Rohingya, Chin, and Kachin documents, 2005-2007, VI. Unocal pipeline materials, VII. Corporate, resource extraction, and environmental issues, VIII. Press binders and tourism issues, IX. HIV/AIDS, X. Posters, calendars, drawings, and XI. Video cassettes.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the South East Asia Collection Curator, 2015.
Human rights -- Burma; Indigenous peoples -- Burma; Mirante, Edith T.; Project Maje
- United States and Asian press, government reports, and documents, 1960-1993; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series is divided chronologically into three sub-series: 1960-1989, 1990-1991, and 1992-1993. The topics covered in this series are diverse, ranging from narcotics and military issues; trade, labor and human rights; to international perspectives on the politics of Burma's military regime.
  - 1960-1989
    - Karens, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - US Press, pre-1986, 1982-1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Asia press - magazines - pre-1986, 1960-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
    - Documents, 1961-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
    - Thai newspapers, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Democracy and human rights documents, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 2-4)
    - Asiaweek and Far Eastern Economic Review clippings, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - US Press, narcotics and military issues, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Indigenous and human rights documents, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 3-6)
    - National democratic front ethnic alliance news articles, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - US Media on Burmese government and politics, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
    - US academic and NGO documents, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Asia media - Shan issues, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Newsweek, Far Eastern Economic Review, and Asiaweek Magazines, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Human rights, development newsbriefs, clippings, and memos, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 2-4)
    - MA Thesis, indigenous issues, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - The International Center, Burma in Brief, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Drugs, International Security and US Public Policy, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Assorted US magazine clippings, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 3-5)
    - Documents on Australia-Burma relations, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Democratic front/students' coalition and Karen documents, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Burma-Myanmar name change press clippings, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Washington DC-related documents, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
    - Amnesty International, 1983-1989 (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
  - 1990-1991
    - US news clippings on politics, Buddhism, and human rights, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
    - Bangkok Post clippings, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - B.A. manuscript, Identity, Change, and the Peoples of Burma, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Documents on trade, labor, and human rights, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - International Human Rights Law Group, report on the Myanmar election, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - MA thesis, Opium suppression policies in the Golden Triangle, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Human rights reports and news bulletins, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
    - Assorted US documents on health, democratic, and political issues, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
    - Assorted Asian newspaper clippings, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
    - United States and European media clippings, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Newsletters, reports on democracy, human rights, narcotics, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - Asiaweek, Time, Far East Economic Review clippings, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - NCGUB papers, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Australian media, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Action group and human rights memos, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - International memos and perspectives on Burma, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Burma rights movement for action and assorted documents, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Assorted documents on crises in Burma, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Democracy and human rights advocacy memos, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Basic narcotics issues, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - United Nations Documents, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Assorted documents, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 1992-1993
    - Australian press copies and clippings, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Thai press copies and clippings, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 2-4)
    - US press copies and clippings, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Convention and conference reports and newsletters, various issues, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 1-5)
    - Far Eastern Economic Review, Asiaweek, and various magazine clippings, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Human rights and and political newsletters and reports, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 1-6)
    - Thai press clippings and copies, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 1-3)
    - Human rights/drugs bulletins and reports, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 1-3, Box 17, Folder 4-5)
    - US/Australia/Europe press, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Asia/Australian media, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - The Nation, Bangkok Post, and assorted Thai media, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Documents on drug policy in Burma and Southeast Asia, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Newsletters and report manuscripts, various issues, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 2-6, Box 20, Folder 1-4)
- Newsletters, press, documents, and women's issues, 1973-1995; Series II
  Series II consists of newsletters and press from Burmese and various international outlets, including The Dawn, Burma Review, Burma Times, Burma Bulletin, Burma News, Burma Monitor, The Irrawaddy, The New York Times, Bangkok Post, The West Australian, and The Economist. Documents include action memos and field reports, and attend to issues of ethnicity and gender.
  - Dawn, Karen, Burma Review, Burma Times, Burma Bulletin, and assorted newsletters, 1973-1993 (Box 21, Folder 1-7, Box 22, Box 23)
  - New York Times, Bankgkok Post, the West Australian and other newsclippings, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 1-3)
  - Newsletters relating to Buddhism, 1988-1990 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Burma Issues, Burma Monitor, and Mon Relief, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - The Irrawaddy, Burma Review, Burma Affairs, 1993-1994 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Geopolitical Drug Dispatch, Burma Focus, Dawn, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Committee for restoration of democracy in Burma newsletters, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - The Economist, New York Times, Bangkok Post, assorted international press, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Assorted documents and newsletters, 1993-1994 (Box 27, Folder 1-3, Box 26, Folder 1-5)
  - Burmese resistance documents, 1994 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Military development in Burma, 1994 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Burma (Myanmar) at the United Nations General Assembly, 1994 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Forced labour in Burma: A collection of Documents, 1994 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Free Suu Kyi Free Burma, 1994 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Burmese refugee documents, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Ethnicity issues, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Assorted action memos, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Memos and field reports, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Asian press photocopies and clippings, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 1-3)
  - US Press photocopies and clippings, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 4-5)
  - CRDB, Democracy, Burma Review, Burma News, Burma Update, and Freedom Fighter newsletters, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Friends of Burma at Harvard, Mon National Relief Committee newsletters, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Burma Issues, The Irrawaddy, and Burma Alerts newsletters, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Burma Debate, Dawn, and Burma Issues newsletters, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Asian press clippings, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Human rights reports, newsletters, and documents, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 1-5, Box 34, Folder 1, Box 33)
  - Women's issues, 1995 (Box 34, Folder 2-3)
- Newsletters, press, documents, and Project Maja reports, 1996-1997; Series III
  This series includes a variety of newsletters, press documents, and reports from Project Maje, the Mon National Relief Committee, Karen Human Rights Group, Human Rights Watch, and other entities. Topics include human rights abuses and political dissent, forced relocation efforts, and environmental issues.
  - Assorted memos and reports on human rights and dissent in Burma, 1996 (Box 36, Folder 1-2, Box 35, Folder 1-5)
  - Use of Aircraft by SLORC and Shan forced relocation briefing documents, 1996 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - EarthRights, Burma Issues, Burma Alert, Burma Debate, Burma Update, Harvard, Irrawaddy, and Dawn Newsletters, 1996 (Box 36, Folder 4-5, Box 37, Folder 1-2)
  - Asian Press, 1996 (Box 37, Folder 3-4)
  - US Press, 1996 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Assorted human rights, environment reports and files, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 1-3)
  - Various international press clippings, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Burma Monitor, CRDB, Mon National Relief Committee, Human Rights Watch, Burma Links reports and newsletters, 1997 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - The Irrawaddy, Burma Monitor, Mon National Relief Committee, and other newsletters, 1997 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Karen Human Rights Group reports and accompanying materials, 1997 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Karen human rights abuse reports/testimonies, 1997 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Project Maje reports, 1996 (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
  - Human Rights dialogue, Forum of Democratic Leaders in the Asia Pacific, and assorted Burmese newsletters, 1997 (Box 40, Folder 3)
- Assorted Documents, 1998-2004; Series IV
  These documents vary widely in content and scope. Highlights include newsletters such as the Asia pacific Advocate, Burma Debate, Burma Issues, and Mon forum. Additional materials include documents on the Free Burma movement.
  - Documents, Newsletters on ethnic minority issues, Christian minstries, and human rights, 2003-2004 (Box 41, Folder 1-6)
  - Burma (Myanmar) at the UN Commission on Human Rights, Abuse Under Orders, and accompanying documents, 2001 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Burma Debate and accompanying documents, 2000-2002 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - The Irrawaddy and accompanying newsbriefs, 2002 (Box 42, Folder 3-4)
  - Forced Labor, Karen Human Rights Group, International Crisis Group reports and accompanying documents, 2002 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - International Crisis Group, the Politics of Humanitarian Aid, and accompanying news clippings and reports, 2002 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Karen Human Rights Group Reports: Orders to Villages, Peace Villages and Hiding Villages, Convict Porters, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Humanitarian issues in Burma, assorted reports and newsletters, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Various international and Burmese news clippings, reports, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - The Irrawaddy and accompanying press, 2001 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Amnesty International, Burma Issues on human rights, accompanying press clippings, 2001 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Human rights, social, and economic assessments, 1999 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Karen human rights reports: False Peace, Orders to Villages, and accompanying documents, 1999 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Human rights press printouts and clippings, 1999 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - The Mon Forum, Diakonia, Cultural Survival, and The Irrawaddy newsletters, 2000 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Free Burma Now, Burma Debate, Burma Debate, the Mon Forum, and Diakonia newsletters, 2000 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Mon reports, Burma Monitor, Committee for Restoration of Democracy in Burma, and Irrawaddy newsletters, 1998 (Box 45, Folder 1-2)
  - Burma Issues, Monitor, and Debate, Mon Reports, and Diakronia newsletters, 1998 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Press clippings on American and Burmese human rights detainees, 1998 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - The Asia Pacific Advocate, Burma Debate, Burma Issues, and Mon Forum newsletters, 1999-2000 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Various pamphlets, reports, and newsletters on campaigns for Burma, 1999 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - The Forum of Democratic Leaders in the Asia-Pacific, Diakronia, and accompanying memos, 1998 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Independent Reports by the Karen Human Rights Group, 1998 (Box 46, Folder 2-3)
  - Various free Burma letters, newsletters, and documents, 1998 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Alternative ASEAN Network on Burma and Burma Issues documents, 2004 (Box 46, Folder 5)
- Arakan, Rohingya, Chin, and Kachin documents, 1976-2007; Series V
  These assorted memos, newsletters, and news clippings focus on some of Burma's ethnic and religious minority groups, specifically the Arakan, Rohingya, Chin, Kachin, and Christian communities.
  - Various memos, newsletters, and newsclippings, 2005-2007 (Box 47, Folder 1-6)
  - Rohingyha documents, 1991-1999 (Box 48, Folder 1-2)
  - Arakan (Rakhine) issues, 1986-2004 (Box 48, Folder 3-4)
  - Mon Forum and other assorted documents, 2007 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Arakanese research journal, 2001 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Rohingya newsletters, 1988-2000 (Box 49, Folder 1-2)
  - Rohingya documents, 1976-2003 (Box 49, Folder 3-6)
  - Burma/India issues, 1986-1997 (Box 50, Folder 1-3)
  - Chin documents, 1988-2005 (Box 51, Folder 1-2)
  - Chin newsletters, 1992-2004 (Box 51, Folder 3-4)
  - Christians in Burma, 1986-2001 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Drawings by Kachin school children, undated (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Kachin documents, 1945, 1983-2006 (Box 52, Folder 3-6)
- Unocal pipeline materials on lawsuits, charter revocation, and the environment, 1992-2006; Series VI
  This series consists of Unocal Pipeline materials on lawsuits, charter revocation, and the environment. Highlights include press releases, memos, and critical coverage of Unocal's activities in India and Burma.
  - Unocal pipeline press clippings, newsletters, and memos, 1992-2006 (Box 54, Folder 1-4, Box 53, Box 55, Box 56, Folder 1-5)
  - Unocal Charter, 1998 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Unocal press photocopies and clippings, 1993-1994 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Unocal in India, 1994-2000 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Unocal pipeline environmental effects, 1992-1997 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Unocal lawsuit, 1996-1997 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Total pipeline, 1992-1996 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Press kits, Burma petroleum, 1994-1996 (Box 58, Folder 2-3)
- Corporate, resource extraction, and environmental issues, 1976-2007; Series VII
  This series contains information on other oil companies including Atlantic Richfield Company (ARCO), Texaco, and AMOCO Corporation centered on the environmental and economic effects of their activities in Burma. Additional materials attend human rights issues associated with other industries such as logging, dams, mining, shipping, and garment factories.
  - Atlantic Richfield Company (ARCO), 1994-1998 (Box 59, Folder 1-2)
  - Texaco, 1976-1998 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - AMOCO Corporation, 1990-1994 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Sanctions, boycotts, economy, 1989-2001 (Box 60, Folder 1-3)
  - Pepsi, 1990-1996 (Box 60, Folder 4-5)
  - Other petroleum companies, 1987-1999 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Selective purchasing, 1989-2000 (Box 61, Folder 1-3)
  - Amicus briefs, Massachusetts Burma law, 1999 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Garment industry, 1992-2001 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Divestment, 1994-2001 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - LaSalle Bank - Algemene Bank Nederland/Amsterdam and Rotterdam Bank, 1998-2000 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Logging issues, 1983-2004 (Box 63, Folder 1, Box 62, Folder 1-6)
  - Dams, 1989-2007 (Box 63, Folder 2-3)
  - Other corporations, 1991-2000 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Shipping labor, 1993-1995 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Mining issues, 1990-1995 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - MA thesis, Ecological abuse of power, 1991 (Box 64, Folder 2)
- Press binders and tourism issues, 1983-2002; Series VIII
  These files contain news items from the Asian process focused on effects of tourism on local communities in Burma and greater mainland Southeast Asia.
  - Thai newspapers, 1988 uprising (Box 65, Folder 1-4)
  - Thai newspapers, 1989-1991 (Box 66, Folder 1-5, Box 68, Box 67, Folder 1-4)
  - Asian newspapers, 1989-1990 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Asian Magazines, 1988-1991 (Box 69, Folder 1-3)
  - Opium and security policy in postwar policy in postwar Asia, 1991 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Teak war, seacoast environmental issues, 1989-1990 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Tourism files, 1983-2002 (Box 70, Folder 1-4)
- HIV/AIDS, Series IX
  This series deals exclusively with the effects of the HIV/AIDS epidemic in Burma and greater Asia. Consisting primarily of news clippings and items, the series addresses issues of prostitution, drug use, and local and international efforts to combat the epidemic.
  - HIV/AIDS issues, 1990-2001 (Box 72, Folder 1-2, Box 71, Folder 1-5)
- Posters, calendars, drawings, 1984-2004; Series X
  This format-based series consists entirely of graphic materials including posters, calendars, and drawings. Noteworthy items include calendars published by ethnic resistance groups, anti-SLORC posters, and materials commemorating the March 13th students' movement.
  - Burma the Golden Land, the Golden Lie, undated; 2 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Mandalay Palace forced labor, 1996 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Lines of Fire, 1990 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Project Maje - Free Burma, undated (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Knu Calendar, 1984; 2.0 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Karen National Union Calendar, 1990-1994; 3.0 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Free Burma Project Maje, undated; 1.0 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Should ASEAN Welcome SLORC?, undated (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Women of Burma Resisting the Military Regime, undated; 1.0 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - 10th Anniversary of March 13 students' movement in Burma, undated; 1.0 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - One voice for all who suffer and struggle for human rights in Burma, undated; 1.0 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Shoot to Kill: the Burma Connection, circa 2000 - circa 2004 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Committee for Publicity of People's Struggle in Monland, undated (Box 74)
  - Free Burma 1995, 1.0 (Box 74)
- Videocassettes, 1980-2005; Series XI
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  This format-driven series of VHS cassettes is broad in scope, and includes news broadcasts, documentaries, and interviews from the Western and Southeast Asian press. Materials focus on political and human rights issues, environmental issues, corporate protests and resource extraction, child soldiers, and election coverage.
  - Free Burma Coalition, circa 1990's; 1 (Box 75)
  - Day of Prayer for Burma, 2003; 1 (Box 76)
  - Interviews with Burmese students, Oregon public broadcasting, circa 1990's; 1 (Box 77)
  - Unocal Protest, 1998 September 10; 1 (Box 78)
  - Guns, Drugs and Liberation: The Battle for Burma and Democracy, circa 1990's; 1 (Box 79)
  - Aung San Suu Kyi, circa 1990's; 1 (Box 80)
  - Road to Nowhere by Asia Works, 1999; 1 (Box 81)
  - Burmese student demonstration, video report (master with subtitles), 1990's; 1 (Box 82)
  - Caught in the Crossfire, circa 1990's; 1 (Box 83)
  - UNOCAL in Burma, Oregon public broadcasting, circa 1990's; 1 (Box 84)
  - Unocal Nightline episode, 2000 March 28; 1 (Box 85)
  - Recalling the Jungle, Japanese Broadcasting Corporation, 1989 June 18; 1 (Box 86)
  - ABC News, Nightline coverage of Burma, 1995 July; 1 (Box 87)
  - Drummond's Khun Sa documentary, PBS Intercom, circa 1990's; 1 (Box 88)
  - North American newsbroadcasts on Burma, 1988; 1 (Box 89)
  - Let's Make the World a Better Place! 1999 Unocal Annual MTG and Human Rights Review, 2 (Box 90)
  - Free Burma Rangers, "Love in Action" by Freedom Films, circa 1980's - circa 1990's; 1 (Box 91)
  - NYU boycott of Pepsi, CNN, 1996 April 22-24; 1 (Box 92)
  - When Spiders Unite, made for the Free Burma Coalition, circa 1980's - circa 1990's; 1 (Box 93)
  - Free Burma Campaign Pepsi Boycott, circa 1990's; 1 (Box 94)
  - Birth: Voices from the 1988 Uprising in Burma (Nonviolence Empowerment organization, inc), 1 (Box 95)
  - Day of Prayer for Burma, Free Burma Rangers, 2004; 1 (Box 96)
  - Pepsi, circa 1980's - circa 1990's; 1 (Box 97)
  - Burma elections footage, 1990; 1 (Box 98)